[Waco] Branch Davidians: Mark Swett collection, Inclusive: 1921-2001, undated, Bulk: 1978-1993
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Mark Swett collection
Inclusive: 1921-2001, undated, Bulk: 1978-1993
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3520
Branch Davidians
5 document boxes and 15 oversized tape boxes.
The [Waco] Branch Davidians: Mark Swett collection consists of materials collected by Mark Swett concerning the Branch Davidians. This collection includes personal correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, books, audio recordings, and secondary literature of the Branch Davidians and their key leaders. There is a particular emphasis on David Koresh throughout the collection.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
The religious sects known as the Davidians and Branch Davidians were the products of a reform movement within the Seventh-Day Adventist Church. Problems began when a group of Adventists, led by Bulgarian immigrant Victor Houteff, began to challenge the traditional hierarchy of the denomination. Houteff claimed to have received personal revelations from God and published his controversial views in a book entitled The Shepherd’s Rod (1932). Houteff and his followers, the Davidians, believed that the spiritual gift of prophecy was necessary for effective leadership so that King David’s earthly kingdom could be re-established on earth prior to the second coming of Jesus Christ. After the leaders of the Seventh-Day Adventist Church excommunicated his sect, Houteff moved to Waco, Texas, and continued to preach until his death in 1955.
Upon Houteff’s death, the Davidians splintered into sects. The new Branch Davidians, under Ben and Lois Roden, emerged as an offshoot. The Rodens would lead the Branch Davidians well into the 1980's. Some of their work including sermons, pamphlets, and personal correspondence are found in the Mark Swett Collection.
Despite decades of relative peace, the 1980's brought about division within the Branch Davidian sect. A newcomer named Vernon Howell had joined the Branch in 1981. Three years later, a schism occurred within the Branch Davidians, with Howell leading his own group of followers to a new site in Palestine, Texas. Through a series of confrontations between Howell and George Roden, the son of Ben and Lois Roden, control of the Branch Davidians’ headquarters in Waco passed to Howell who legally changed his name to David Koresh in 1990. Rumors concerning polygamy, abuse, and arms dealing within the Branch Davidian group aroused the suspicions of the federal government. Thus, federal agencies such as the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives began to monitor the group.
In response to a stockpiling of illegal weapons, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives secured a search warrant for the investigation of the Branch Davidians’ compound near Waco, Texas. From February 28th until April 19th, 1993, Branch Davidians under the leadership of David Koresh resisted federal agents’ attempts to storm their Mount Carmel Center. The fifty-day siege ended when the compound erupted in flames, killing David Koresh and most of his followers.
Mark Swett is a private collector who studied religious cults in U.S. history. As a result of this passion, he has quickly become one of the most renowned researchers in the case of the Branch Davidians. He was particularly interested in the figure of David Koresh and the divinity attributed to him. Although he was a career insurance salesman in Westbrook, Maine, Swett devoted his time and energy into researching the Waco Branch Davidians via the internet and personal correspondence. He created his own web site entitled “Waco: Never Again!” which has since been removed. Although Swett believed that the fire was ultimately the responsibility of the Branch Davidians, he claimed to be an unbiased researcher seeking only to know the truth of the situation. Because of his vast knowledge of Koresh and the Branch Davidians, Swett has been personally involved in interviews, trials, and theatrical productions about the Waco Siege. In 2003, Swett sold his vast collection to Baylor University so that others could use the primary source materials that he had amassed.
Scope and Content
The [Waco] Branch Davidians: Mark Swett collection was purchased from Mr. Swett in February 2003. The collection begins with printed materials from 1921 during a time when the Seventh-Day Adventist Church was torn by internal divisions, and concludes in 2001 with a film adaptation of the infamous siege of Mount Carmel Center. The bulk of the materials describe the transition of power from Benjamin and Lois Roden to Vernon Howell, later David Koresh. These materials range from Swett’s own personal correspondence with the survivors to books, magazines, newspaper clippings, and religious pamphlets. The focal point of this collection is the massive compilation of audio cassettes that includes sermons prior to 1993 as well as 911 calls and interviews conducted during the siege itself.
Arrangement
There was an inventory prior to processing, but the collection itself lacked organization at the series level. The [Waco] Branch Davidians: Mark Swett collection is arranged into 4 series: I. Correspondence, II. Literary Productions, III. Photographic Materials, and IV. Audio Recordings.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3520. Acquired 2003-02-04
Related Resources
Items in related collections
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Ron Armstrong collection, Inclusive: 1931-1960, undated, Bulk: 1931-1933
[Waco] Branch Davidians: "The Facts About Mt. Carmel" Exhibit collection, Inclusive: 1961-2004, undated, Bulk: 1993-1994
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Robert F. Darden III collection, Inclusive: 1932-1993, undated, Bulk:1985-1993, undated
[Waco] Branch Davidians: William Smith collection, Inclusive: 1984-1998, undated, Bulk: 1993-1995
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Amo Paul Roden papers, Inclusive: 1946-2008, 2017, undated, Bulk: 1993-2003
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Kenneth G.C. Newport
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Kirk D. Lyons collection, Inclusive: 1979-1998, undated, Bulk: 1993-1995
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Mount Carmel Seventh Day Adventist collection, Inclusive: 1938-1998, undated, Bulk: 1959-1961; 1996-1997
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Joe Robert collection, Inclusive: 1932-1997, undated, Bulk: 1979-1995
[Waco] Branch Davidians: Kenneth G.C. Newport
Related references
Kerstetter, Todd. “‘That’s Just the American Way’: The Branch Davidian Tragedy and Western Religious History.” Western Historical Quarterly vol. 35, no. 4 (2004 Winter): 453-471.
Lawson, Ronald. “Seventh-Day Adventist Responses to Branch Davidian Notoriety: Patterns of Diversity within a Sect Reducing Tension with Society.” Journal for the Scientific Study of Religion vol. 34, no. 3 (1995 September): 323-341.
“Local Man Offers Insight into Waco.” Religion News Report vol. 4, no. 223 (2000 July 4). Accessed August 3, 2011.
Rosenfeld Jean E., Mary Z. Stange, and Ivan Strenski. “Understanding Waco.” Journal of the American Academy of Religion vol. 62, no. 3 (1994 Autumn): 919-946.
Wright, Stuart A. “A Decade after Waco: Reassessing Crisis Negotiations at Mount Carmel in Light of New Government Disclosures.” Nova Religio vol. 7, no. 2 (2003 November): 101-110.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Koresh, David, 1959-1993.
Subjects (Organizations)
Branch Davidians.
Subjects
Mount Carmel Center, Waco, Tex.; Seventh Day Adventists -- History.; Waco Branch Davidian Disaster, Tex., 1993.
Genres
Articles.; Correspondence.; Essays.; Interviews (Sound recordings); Notes (documents); Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Sermons.; Video recordings.
- Correspondence, 1956-2000; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence from some of the most influential Branch Davidians including former leaders Ben and Lois Roden. The materials are in good condition.
  - General, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jaime Castillo, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graeme Craddock, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clive Doyle, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Livingston Fagan, 1993-February 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Livingston Fagan, 1995 May-November (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Livingston Fagan, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Livingston Fagan, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ben Roden, 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ben Roden, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ben Roden, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ben Roden, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lois Roden, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lois Roden, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Literary Productions, 1921-2000, undated; 2
  This series contains books, pamphlets, sermons, notes, essays, and other literary productions pertaining to the Davidian and Branch Davidians sects. The writings and sermons of David Koresh are prominent throughout. The materials are in good condition.
  - Investigation into the Activities of the Federal Law Enforcement Agencies Toward the Branch Davidians, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Koreshanity, The New Age Religion: Koreshan Foundation, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Book: Mt. Carmel, The Unseen Reality: Livingston Fagan, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Book One: David Koresh (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Book One: David Koresh (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Book Two: David Koresh (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Book Two: David Koresh (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Question and Answer Study Guide: David Koresh (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Book: Seven Seals: Question and Answer Study Guide: David Koresh (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Book: Sinister Twilight: Ron Cole, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Book: Steps to Christ: Ellen G. White, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book: The Decoded Message of the Seven Seals of the Book of Revelation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Periodical: Shekinah, 1980-1981 February (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Periodical: Shekinah, 1981 April-August (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Periodical: Shekinah, 1981 October-December (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Periodical: Shekinah, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Periodical: Time, 1993 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Periodical: U.S. News, 1993 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Periodical: The Watchman Expositor, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlets, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pamphlets, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlets, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pamphlets (1 of 2), 1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pamphlets (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Printed Materials: Ben Roden, 1947-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Printed Materials: Brother and Sister Bunds, 1970-1979 February (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Printed Materials: Brother and Sister Bunds, 1979 June-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Printed Materials: Victor Houteff, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials: Victor Houteff, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials: Living Waters Branch, 1979-1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials: Sabbath School, 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials: “Wanted” Material, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sermons: General (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Sermons: General (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sermons: Ron Cole, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sermons: David Koresh, 1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden, 1958 April-June (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden, 1958 July-1959 September (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden, 1959 October-1960 March (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden, 1960 April-1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden (1 of 2), 1965, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sermons: Ben Roden (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sermons: Ellen G. White, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Essays: Don Adair, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Essays: J. Phillip Arnold, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Essays: Renos Avraam, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Essays: Marc Breault: “Vernon Howell and the Seven Seals”, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Essays: Marc Breault: “The Return of David Koresh”, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Essays: Marc Breault: “From Israel to Mount Carmel”, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Essays: Marc Breault: “Vernon Howell and the 1995 Deadline”, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Essays: Marc Breault: “A Study on Job 38”, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Essays: Jaime Castillo: General, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Essays: Jaime Castillo: General, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Essays: Jaime Castillo: “Setting a Foundation”, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Essays: Jaime Castillo: “Come and See”, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan, 1993-1994 June (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan, 1994 November (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan, 1995-1997 June (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan, 1997 July-November (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (1 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (2 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (3 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (4 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (5 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Essays: Livingston Fagan (6 of 6), 1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Essays: Dennis Hokama: “The Ghost from Adventism’s Past”, 1993 March (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Essays: Dennis Hokama: “Transcript of the 2/28/87 Howell Video”, 1993 April (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Essays: Dennis Hokama: “Converting the Very Elect”, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Essays: Kevin McCrary, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Essays: Bill Pitts, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Essays: Nancy and Chip Tatum, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Essays: Flaming Sword, 1921-1922, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Publications: General, 1988-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Publications: Religious, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: FBI, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: Charles Pace and Amo Roden, 1973, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: Lois Roden, 1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: Noah’s Ark and Mrs. Joseph Warren, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Scripture, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Seventh-Day Adventist Association, 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: Waco Siege, 1993-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Livingston Fagan: “Mt. Carmel, The Unseen Reality”, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Dearly Beloved Dad” (1 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Dearly Beloved Dad” (2 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Dearly Beloved Dad” (3 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Dearly Beloved Dad” (4 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Dearly Beloved Dad” (5 of 5), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Lay Members” (1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “Lay Members” (2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “The Seventh Step” (1 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “The Seventh Step” (2 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Notes: David Koresh: “The Seventh Step” (3 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Notes: Ruth Riddle (1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Notes: Ruth Riddle (2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Photographic Materials, 1993-2001, undated; 3
  This series contains a photograph and videos pertaining to the Branch Davidians, primarily during the siege of Mount Carmel in 1993. The materials are in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print; Video home system (VHS) tapes
  - Photograph: David Koresh’s Tombstone, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Video Tape: Current Affair Special: “The Madman of Waco”, 1994 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Video Tape: David Thibodeau: Independence, Missouri, 1994 August 11 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Video Tape: David Koresh Bible Study, undated (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Video Tape: Mount Carmel Center during Siege, undated (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Video Tape: Vernon Howell Bible Study: Los Angeles, California, 1987 February 28 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Video Tape: James Scott Trimm: “The Seven Seals”, 1994 September 10 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Video Tape: “Daughter of Zion”, 1997 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Video Tape: “Branch Davidian Seminar:” Washington, D.C., 1993 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Video Tape: “The F.L.I.R. Project”, 2001 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Video Tape: “Waco: A New Revelation”, 1999 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Video Tape: “Waco: The Rules of Engagement”, 1997 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Video Tape: Mount Carmel Security Camera View, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #1, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #2, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #3, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #4, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #5, 1993 March 11 (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #6, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #8, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #9, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Video Tape: Stowers Waco Tape #11, undated (Box 18 OVZ, Folder 10)
- Audio Recordings, 1976-1995, undated; 4
  This series contains hundreds of audiotapes concerning the Branch Davidians. Materials include sermons by various leaders as well as recordings of the siege. The materials are in good condition.
  - Cassette Tape: Ben Roden: “The Assyrian”, August 13, 1977 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Cassette Tape: Mr. Poppit: St. Paul’s Church, September 1976 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Cassette Tape: #4012, March 21, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden, May 14, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Cassette Tape: “7 Seals of Trumpets”, May 22-24, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden, May 29, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Cassette Tape: NPR Radio, June 20, 1995 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “3 Angels” and “Grains”, July 4, 1976 and July 3, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Cassette Tape: “Sign of Jonah”, October 2-3, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Cassette Tape: Ben Roden’s Funeral, October 26, 1978 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “Overall Aspect of Res by Faith”, November 24-25, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “7 Thunders”, February 5, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “7 Thunders” and “Degeneration First Fruits”, February 15, 1979 and July 6, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Cassette Tape: General, February 27, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: Isaiah 11, March 3-4, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “Sinful Flesh” and Clive Doyle, March 22, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - Cassette Tape: General, April 16, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - Cassette Tape: General, April 29-May 1, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 18)
  - Cassette Tape: RF, April 29-May 1, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 19)
  - Cassette Tape: General, May 24, 1979 and May 23, 1991 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 20)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden, May 25, 1979 and May 29, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tape: Trip to Israel, May 28-June 1, 1980 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 22)
  - Cassette Tape: Pentecost, June 2, 1979 and June 29, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 23)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “Times of Latter Day Rain”, October 29, 1979 and October 31, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 24)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “Truth & Knowledge”, May 2-3, 1979 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 25)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden: “If a Man Die Will He Live Again?”, November 28, 1982 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 26)
  - Cassette Tape: Merkobah, December 10, 1982 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 27)
  - Cassette Tape: Wordell Jones: Merkobah, December 17, 1982 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 28)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell: Isaiah 56-57, undated (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 29)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell: Revelation 10 and 14, undated (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 30)
  - Cassette Tape: Questions and Answers: Perry, Clive, and Brother Boyd, February 14, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 31)
  - Cassette Tape: Lois Roden, May 14, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 32)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell (1 of 2), September 11, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 33)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell (2 of 2), September 11, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 34)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell, September 13, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 35)
  - Cassette Tape: DK: Isaiah 56-57, James 1, and Proverbs 23, September 14, 1983 (Box 6 OVZ, Folder 36)
  - Cassette Tape: SW4, undated (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Need to Rest”, October 10, 1983 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell, October 10, 1983 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell, October 15, 1983 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Cassette Tape: Ben and Lois Roden, April 19, 1984 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Ezekiel 21, October 19, 1984 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “The 7th Angel Enters into Rest”, January 30, 1985 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Seven Eyes”, February 4, 1985 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Judge What I Say”, February 4, 1985 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Seven Angels”, February 4, 1986 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Psalm 68 and Isaiah 42, March 12, 1986 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Sabbath (1 of 2), March 15, 1986 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Sabbath: Tape 2 of 2, March 15, 1986 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Daniel 7, June 14, 1986 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Letter to Steve Schneider and Wisconsin Brethren, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Confusion 2”, July 18, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Revelation 13, July 23, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell: “Root of Jessie Gentile Girls”, August 24, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 18)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell: “The Bird”, August 24, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 19)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Assyrians”, January 10, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 20)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell, August 24, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 21)
  - Cassette Tape: Vernon Howell: “Feelings-Fun Being Last Adventist”, August 24, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 22)
  - Cassette Tape: General, August 24, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 23)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Joel and Daniel, 1987 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 24)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: Jonah, April 25, 1989 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 25)
  - Cassette Tape: David Koresh: “Vernon’s Dream”, April 24, 1989 (Box 7 OVZ, Folder 26)